homeone.com.au 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy Outline

This policy summarizes how Homeone Australia & New Zealand (ABN 46 625 367 703, "We", "Our", "Us" and "homeone®"), which operates homeone.com.au (this "Site"), commits to providing Members and Advertisers of the Site with peace of mind pertaining to any personal information You supply to Us. 

As We value users' privacy, it is Our intention that Your personal information in connection with your use of our services, including those offered through our websites, email and mobile applications (collectively, "Services") will be handled in accordance with Our Privacy Policy and the Australian Privacy Principles. 

This Privacy Policy describes:

  * What personal information is collected;
  * The purpose of collecting your information;
  * How your collected information is used;
  * Disclosing personal information to others;
  * How your personal information is stored;
  * How we protect your personal information;
  * Accessing and updating your personal information;
  * How to complain about privacy concerns; and
  * Contacting homeone.com.au

#### What is personal information?

Personal information means information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable:

  * Whether the information or opinion is true or not; and
  * Whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.

Personal information does not include anonymous or aggregated information that does not identify an individual personally. 

#### What personal information do we collect?

homeone® gathers non-personal aggregated information for the purpose of measuring and analysing website traffic data.

homeone® also collects personal information that Visitors, Members and Advertisers knowingly or voluntarily submit to this Site for the purpose the information is submitted or for such other secondary purposes that are related to the primary purpose, unless homeone® disclose other uses in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection.

Examples of personal information collected when you use Our Services are as follows:

**Joining as a Member**  
To join as a member we request information such as a unique username, your email address and collect your IP address. Optionally, as a member you may choose to provide additional information such as your occupation, website, suburb or state. 

**Joining as a Member via Facebook or Google+**  
We collect your email address and use your Facebook or Google+ profile photo. We do not use your Facebook or Google+ name, so we ask you to provide a new username. You may choose to manually provide additional information such as your occupation, website, suburb or state.

**Contacting an Advertiser**  
When contacting a directory advertiser at homeone.com.au using the Contact Us, Ask a Question or Get Quote form we collect your name, email, phone, suburb and IP address. 

**Requesting Tickets to Home Shows**  
Members are asked for a name and a postal adddress. 

**Pro Advertiser Registration**  
Full name, email address, contact number, password and postal address, and credit card details (credit card name, c/c number, c/c expiry date, CVV). 

**Basic Advertiser Registration**  
Full name, email address, contact number, password and postal address. 

**Basic Advertiser; Pay Per Lead (PPL)**  
To process once-off payment for each lead credit card details are collected (C/C number, C/C expiry date and CVV). 

**Making enquiries to homeone.com.au**  
Name (or username if logged in), email address, contact number, IP address and a trading name if the nature of enquiry is advertising related. 

#### Why do we collect personal information?

The personal information we collect generally enables us to:

  * 1\. Provide and improve our Services for all Members and Advertisers.
  * 2\. Offer a personalised experience at our Site
  * 3\. Deliver targeted advertising, marketing or service updates.
  * 3\. Present you with localised information.
  * 4\. Contact you directly about your Member or Advertiser account either by email, phone and / or postal mail.
  * 5\. Provide customer service and forum support. 
  * 5\. Better prevent against spam or activities in breach of Site Terms of Use, Advertiser Service Agreement or Forum Guidelines. 

#### How is your collected information used?

Our uses of personal information collected about Members and Advertisers are as follows: 

**Members**

  * To establish Member registration  

  * To send verification emails such as member activation, password resets or username changes.  

  * To provide Members with login access and use of our Services  

  * To enable auto-creation of Member profile pages which displays the Member's chosen username at a minimum including the display of any optionally provided personal information (such as a suburb or occupation)  

  * To provide you with location-specific services such as advertising, search results and other geographically personalised content.  

  * To communicate mandatory account or service notifications, newsletters, notifications of personal messages (PM's), topic replies and social interactions.  

  * To indicate and publicly display your username (including optionally provided personal information for public display), when you're online, against topics you watch, Member or Advertisers you follow, and Content you like, share and comment on.
  *   * To cross-reference IP addresses against spam blacklists and to internally manage a member restriction list in relation to breaches of Site Terms of Use.

**Advertisers**

  * To facilitate Advertiser registration  

  * To send verification and administrative emails such as Advertiser activations and password resets.  

  * To provide Advertisers with login access and use of our Service.  

  * To enable creation of Advertiser profile pages and associated listings which publicly displays the Advertiser's business contact information and any other Content (such as text, images and video), the Advertisers chooses to voluntarily submit.  

  * To feature Advertisers in services such as advertising, search results and other geographically personalised content.  

  * To communicate mandatory account or service notifications, newsletters, notifications of personal messages (PM's), topic replies and social interactions.  

  * To cross-reference IP addresses against spam blacklists and to internally manage a member restriction list in relation to breaches of Site Terms of Use.

homeone® interfaces with social platform sites such as Facebook, G+, and Twitter. Should you "share" any content from this Site with a social platform, you should review the privacy policy of that platform's service.

 **Social Platforms**

homeone® interfaces with social platform sites such as Facebook, G+, and Twitter. Should you "share" any content from this Site with a social platform, you should review the privacy policy of that platform's service.

#### With whom do we disclose your personal information?

Not linked to personally identifiable information, an aggregate of IP addresses are used to analyze user visitation trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Information that is not personally identifiable may be shared with site visitors, clients, content providers, advertisers, and affiliates. For example, we may share the total value of the number of users that have been exposed to, or clicked on, any advertising over a given period.

We forward your Get Quote, Ask a Question or Contact us form to Advertisers you intend to communicate with. In that circumstance, We forward Your personal information voluntarily submitted in the form by you to those Advertisers in order to meet Your request for goods or services. 

Our forum support members and Admin can view Member IP's and email addresses for the primary purpose of preventing and managing forum abuse and breaches of the Forum Terms of Use.

Payment information inputted at our Site is collected and processed by a contracted third-party merchant gateway, Payway, and stored on their server/s. See [PayWay](https://www.payway.com.au/) website to read their Privacy Policy.

Unless otherwise authorised to do so with Your consent, homeone® does not sell, share, or rent personally identifiable information to third parties other than those contracted by homeone®.

Other than the above, personal information may be disclosed in special situations where homeone® has reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against anyone damaging, injuring, or interfering (intentionally or unintentionally) with Our rights or property, users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. Also, homeone® may disclose personal information when We believe in good faith that the law requires disclosure. 

**Change of ownership**  
In the event homeone.com.au were to merge or be acquired by another company, the new entity would comply with this Privacy Policy. Should this Privacy Policy be amended as a result of new ownership whereby your personal information will be handled differently, you will receive notification of any changes to a forthcoming Privacy Policy. 

#### How is your personal information stored?

**Communication with Advertisers and homeone.com.au**  
Copies of correspondence sent from the Site, that may contain personal information, are stored as archives for record-keeping and back-up purposes only.

**Credit Card Information**  
Credit card details provided over the phone are maintained on site for processing of payment and discarded as soon as payment is processed. Where credit card information is collected on this Site, it is not stored on Our servers at any point as a precautionary safeguard. This information is collected by a contracted third-party merchant gateway, and stored on their server/s. See [PayWay](https://www.payway.com.au/) website to read their Privacy Policy.

#### How do we protect your personal information?

We strive to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personal information submitted to homeone® sites, and We review and update Our security measures in light of current technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure.

We will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect the personal information You may transmit to Us or from Our online products and services. Once We do receive Your transmission, homeone® will also make Our best efforts to ensure its security on Our systems.

In addition, homeone® employees and the contractors who provide services related to Our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us. However, We will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to Your personal information.

All forms associated with any purchase from homeone® pass Your financial details through a secure server using the latest 128-bit SSL (secure sockets layer) encryption technology. If You have an questions regarding Our security policy, please contact Us on 1300 HOME1.

Users may be able to draw connections to personally identify you in association with your Member account should you include enough personal information in the content you post publicly, such as street name, photos of your home, or even based on similar usernames and / or avatars (aka Profile Photos) utilised on other third-party sites that potentially reveals more personal information about you. 

In support of your privacy, We allow pseudonyms as usernames, and in fact, encourage use of never-used-before pseudonyms and avatars.

Private messages you send or receive using our Service remain private to the degree that both sender and receiver commits to keeping the messages private. For example, if you send a message to another Member, that Member in question may choose to publicly post your private message.

Again, in support of your privacy, we strongly advise you avoid disclosing personally identifiable information in private messages.

**Cookies**

Cookies store byte-sized information on Your computer system. It enables homeone® to customize this Site in accordance with Your viewing pleasure preferences. Local storage is more secure, and large amounts of data can be stored locally, without affecting website performance. Unlike cookies, the storage limit is far larger (at least 5MB) and information is not automatically transferred to the server. 

The forum system, Our advertising server, directory, and not limited to, uses cookies and local storage to store information. Also, third parties may place and read cookies on Your browser, or may use web beacons to collect information, in the course of ads being served to You on this website. We use cookies to provide You with a better experience. These cookies allow Us to increase Your security by storing Your session ID and are a way of monitoring single user access. This aggregate, non-personal information is collated and provided to Us to assist in analysing the usage of the site. 

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to this site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

This website uses Display Advertising features (Remarketing and Google Analytics and Interest Reporting) cookies to facilitate the sampled reporting of demographics and interests of its visitors within Google Analytics.

homeone.com.au will not merge, nor aid in the merging of personally-identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information previously collected from Display Advertising. You can opt out of this feature by visiting the following link: [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)

This aggregated information collected is used to improve our services and deliver more relevant content to our Users, Members and Advertisers based on aggregated demographic and interest data.

**Links to other Sites**

We provide links to other third-party websites outside of this Site. These linked websites are not under Our control, and We cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of such other websites this Site may link to nor does homeone® make any representations about third party web sites that may be linked to this Site. Before disclosing Your personal information on any other website, homeone® advises You examine the terms and conditions of using that website including its privacy policy.

 **Privacy Policy Updates**

We reserve the right, at Our discretion, to modify or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time. This Privacy Policy is in addition to any other terms and conditions applicable to this Site. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will take effect from the date the Privacy Policy has been updated on this Site.

**Access and update your personal information**

Members and Advertisers of homone.com.au can access and change their personal information at any time in profile settings or dashboard settings respectively.

Should you discover that any information held about You is incorrect yet you're having difficult accessing Your information, please contact Us so we may arrange to have the information updated with correct information.

Forums are public in nature. Once You publish a public post at the forum, You may not be able to edit or remove it. 

#### Complaints about Privacy Concerns

Should you wish to complain about our Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://www.homeone.com.au/contact) and we will respond within a reasonable time frame.

 **Contact Us**

If You have any queries relating to Our Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://www.homeone.com.au/contact) or you may reach us by phone or mail:

 **1300 466 366**

PO BOX 55  
Richmond VIC 3121  
Australia

Should a copy of this Privacy Policy be required in another format please contact us so we may arrange to provide this to you.

For more information about privacy issues in Australia and protecting Your privacy, visit the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner. Details are available at [www.oaic.gov.au](https://www.oaic.gov.au/)
